A Guide to the Evelyn Crary Bacon papers, 1909-1997
Virginia Commonwealth University, Tompkins-McCaw Library
- Organization Files (Box 12-18)
  - National Nursing Accrediting Service - Manual, 1949 (Box-folder 13:23)
  - Northwestern Virginia Health Systems Agency (NWVHSA), 1991-1997 (Box-folder 14:1-8)
    Consists primarily of board and committee meeting minutes.
  - Nurses House, Inc., 1988, 1990 (Box-folder 14:9)
  - Nurses' Settlement & Instructive Visiting Nurses Association, Richmond, Virginia (Box-folder 14:10)
  - Richmond Area Community Council, Changing Patterns of Health Care Delivery Committee, 1973 (Box-folder 14:11)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia (SCHEV), 1972-1977 (Box-folder 14:12-14)
    These files include continuing education information and nursing manpower studies.
  - Senior Statesman of Virginia, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 14:15)
  - Student Nurses Association of Virginia, 1988, 1990 (Box-folder 14:16)
  - Sigma Theta Tau, 1982, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 14:17)
  - Society for Nursing History, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 14:18)
  - Virginia Advisory Council on Nursing Training, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 14:19-21)
  - Virginia Association of Allied Health Professionals, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 14:22)
  - Virginia Board of Nursing, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 14:23)
  - Virginia Association of Continuing Education in Health Professionals, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 14:24-25)
  - Virginia Committee on Nurse Education, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - Virginia Council on Health and Medical Care (VCHMC), 1955-1983 (Box-folder 15:2-8)
    These files consist primarily of various committee papers and general papers relating to the group.
  - Virginia Department of Health, Task Force on Facilities & Services for Long Term Care, 1988 (Box-folder 15:9)
  - Virginia Department of Mental Hygiene & Hospitals - Subcommittee for Graduate Training in Psychiatric Nursing, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 15:10)
  - Virginia Hospital Association, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 15:11)
  - Virginia League for Nursing, 1955-1997 (Box-folder 15:12-24)
    These files contain materials relating to annual meetings, board and committee meetings, newsletters and general information relating to the group.
  - Virginia League of Nursing & Virginia Nurses Association, Joint History Committee, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 15:25)
  - Virginia Nurses Association (VNA), 1968-1997 (Box-folder 15:26-32; 16:1-27; 17:1-22)
    These files contain papers relating to annual conventions 1975-1997, commission and committee papers including the History Committee from 1976-1997, papers from Districts 1, 4, 5, 7, and 10, publications, and other general papers relating to the group.
  - Virginia Society of Professional Nurses, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 17:23-31)
    These files contain board, committee, and task force papers, publications, and general information about the organization.
  - Virginia State Board of Nursing - Annual Reports 1969-1989 (Box-folder 17:32-33)
  - Virginia Student Nurses Association - Student Nurse of the Year, 1975 (Box-folder 17:34)
    This is a cassette tape recording of the presentations given by the finalists for the award.
  - West Virginia Nurses' Association, 1987 (Box-folder 18:1-2)
    Contains annual convention materials and the Proceedings of the West Virginia Nurses' Association Research Symposium.
  - Westminster-Canterbury of the Blue Ridge, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 18:3-5)
    Contains committee notes mostly from the Health Services Accreditation Committee.
  - Women in the Military Service for America Memorial Foundation, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 18:6)
- Research and Subject Files, 1911-1997 (Box 18-21)
  - Conference and Workshop Files, 1959-1996 (Box 18)
    - Archives & Nursing History Workshop, 1985 (Box-folder 18:7)
    - Conference on Future Patterns of Health Care, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 18:8)
    - Elder Rights Task Force, 1996 (Box-folder 18:9)
    - Health Manpower Conference, 1967 (Box-folder 18:10)
    - History of American Nursing Conference, Proceedings, 1982 and 1984 (Box-folder 18:11)
    - Politics of Caring Conference, 1990 (Box-folder 18:12-13)
    - Southern Regional Education Board Conference, 1976 (Box-folder 18:14)
    - Virginia Humanities Conference - Aging in a Humanistic Perspective, 1986 (Box-folder 18:15)
    - Virginia Nurses Association & Virginia Hospital Association Workshop, 1967 (Box-folder 18:16)
    - Virginia Regional Medical Program, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 18:17)
    - Virginia State Board of Nurse Examiners, Conference & Workshop, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 18:18)
    - Work Conference on Curriculum & Instruction in Associate Degree Programs in Nursing, 1960 (Box-folder 18:19)
    - Workshop for Administrators of University Adult Education, 1968 (Box-folder 18:20)
    - Writer's Institute for Nurses, 1978 (Box-folder 18:21)
  - Subject Files, 1940-1997 (Box 18-20)
    - Aging (Box-folder 18:22)
    - Allied Health Profession (Box-folder 18:23)
    - Allied Health Schools (Box-folder 18:24)
    - Mary Barney Baughman, Biographical Information (Box-folder 18:25)
    - Roy Carpenter Beazley, Biographical Information (Box-folder 18:26)
    - Sadie Heath Cabaniss, Biographical Information (Box-folder 18:27)
    - Collegiate Schools of Nursing, Resource Materials, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 18:28)
    - Dictionary of Virginia Biography, Guidelines and Information, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 18:29)
    - Disaster Nursing (Box-folder 18:30)
    - Lulu K. Wolf Hassenplug, Biographical Information (Box-folder 19:1)
    - Health Care Reform, 1990s (Box-folder 19:2)
    - Health Professional in Higher Education, 1960s (Box-folder 19:3)
    - Virginia Henderson, Biographical Information (Box-folder 19:4)
    - Historical Research and Writing (Box-folder 19:5)
    - Hospital Systems Approach to Patient Care, 1960s (Box-folder 19:6)
    - Joint Commission on Health Care, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 19:7-8)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 19:9-10)
    - Florence Nightingale - Publications (Box-folder 19:11)
    - Notes, Misc. (Box-folder 19:12-13)
    - Nurse-Scientist Programs - Articles, 1968 (Box-folder 19:2)
    - Nursing, 1990s (Box-folder 19:15)
    - Nursing Archives Information and Materials 1990s (Box-folder 19:16)
    - Nursing Articles and Papers, 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 19:17-18)
    - Nursing Baccalaureate Program Information, 1960s (Box-folder 19:19)
    - Nursing Cooperative Education Programs 1967 (Box-folder 19:20)
    - Nursing Curriculum Articles, 1970s (Box-folder 19:21)
    - Nursing Curriculum Development, 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 19:22)
    - Nursing Curriculum Philosophy, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 19:23)
    - Nursing Curriculum Program Examples, 1940s-1990s (Box-folder 19:24)
    - Nursing Education - Financial Aid Suggested Sources (Box-folder 19:25)
    - Nursing Education - General (Box-folder 19:26)
    - Nursing Education - Nontraditional Programs, 1970s (Box-folder 19:27)
    - Nursing History - African Americans (Box-folder 20:1)
    - Nursing History - General (Box-folder 20:2)
    - Nursing History - Materials & Resources (Box-folder 20:3-4)
    - Nursing History - University of Virginia (Box-folder 20:5)
    - Nursing Master's Degree Programs - Resources & Materials (Box-folder 20:6)
    - Nursing Practice - Definition (Box-folder 20:7)
    - Nursing Practice Act - Materials (Box-folder 20:8-9)
    - Nursing School Programs, 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 20:10)
    - Nursing Shortage, 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 20:11)
    - Nursing Standards of Practice, 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 20:12-13)
    - Old Dominion Hospital, Class of 1900 (Box-folder 20:14)
    - Progressive Patient Care, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 20:15)
    - Registered Nurses in Baccalaureate Programs - Resource Materials, 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 20:16)
    - Richmond Professional Institute - History (Box-folder 20:17)
    - Speeches & Lectures, 1958, 1993 (Box-folder 20:18)
    - System Analysis & Education 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 20:19)
    - Teaching Resources (Box-folder 20:20)
    - Theory Building in Nursing, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 20:22)
    - Title I Funding Proposals, 1960s-1990s (Box-folder 20:12-13)
    - Williamsburg Community Hospital, 1980s (Box-folder 20:23)
  - Publications, 1911-1994 (Box 20-21)
    - Governor's Committee on Nursing - Reports, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 20:24)
    - Mental Health Publications, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 20:25-26)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., Health Publications, 1920s-1940s (Box-folder 20:27)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (Box-folder 20:28)
    - Nursing Education Publications, 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 21:1-2)
    - Nursing History Publications 1967-1969 (Box-folder 21:3-4)
    - Reproductive Health Publications, 1911, 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 21:5)
    - Resources for Older People, a Care Handbook, 1994 (Box-folder 21:6)
    - A Study of the Registered Nurse in A Metropolitan Community, (in three parts) 1955-1956 (Box-folder 21:7)